만약 일반적으로 RNNs에 대해서 생각한다면,
매우 일반적이고 전형적인 모델은
If you think about RNNs in general,
they are a very general, trainable model
가변 길이의 sequences을 고정 길이의
vectors로 맵핑하는 것입니다.
that maps variable-length
sequences to fixed-length vectors.
사실, sequence 생성과 논의했던 Beam 검색 덕분에
In fact, thanks to the sequence
generation and Bing search that we've
고정 길이의 vectors를 sequences로
맵핑할 수 있도록 만들어질 수 있습니다.
just discussed, they can also be made to
map fixed-length vectors to sequences.
vector로부터 시작해서, RNN의 상태로 이것을 맵핑하고,
예측 결과물을 생성합니다.
Start from a vector, map it to the state
of your RNN, then produce a prediction.
예측 결과물로부터 샘플을 하거나
Beam search을 사용하고
Then sample from it,
or use Bing search, and
다음 단계를 얻기 위해서 RNN에 그 결과를 되먹입니다.
feed them back into the RNN
to get the next one.
2개의 빌딩 블럭을 가지고 있고
그것들을 함께 꿰맬 수 있습니다.
Now you have those two building blocks,
and you can stitch them together.
임의 길이의 sequences를 다른 임의 길이의
sequences로 맵핑하는 새로운 모델이 주어집니다.
It gives you a new model that maps
sequences of arbitrary lengths to other
sequences of arbitrary length.
그리고 이것은 완벽하게 학습이 가능합니다.
And it's fully trainable.
당신은 무엇으로 할 수 있습니까?
What can you do with?
많은 것들이 있습니다.
Many things.
입력이 영어 단어의 sequence가 있고
Imagine that your input is
a sequence of English words and
프랑스 단어의 sequence가 결과가 되는것을 상상해보자.
you output a sequence of French words.
당신은 기계 번역 시스템을 구축할 수 있습니다.
You've just built a machine
translation system.
필요로 한 모든것은 병렬 말뭉치입니다.
All you need is some parallel text.
입력이 사운드이고 출력이 단어라고 상상해보자.
Imagine that your input is sounds and
your output words.
최종적으로 음성 인식 시스템을 구축할 수 있습니다.
You've just built an end-to-end
speech recognition system.
이 디자인에 다양성을 기반한 실시간 시스템은 존재하고
매우 경쟁력이 있습니다.
Real systems based on variations on this
design exist and are very competitive.
실제적으로, 이것들은 매우 많은 데이터를 필요하고
In practice,
they do require a lot of data and
매우 잘 동작하기 위해서는 많은 연산이 필요합니다.
a lot of compute to work very well.
우리는 기본적으로 이미지를 vector로
맵핑하는 conv nets에 대해서 논의했었습니다.
We've also talked about conv nets,
which basically map images
into vectors that represent
the content of that image.
그래서, conv net을 가지고 있고, 이것과 RNN이 연결된다면
무슨 일이 일어나는지 상상해보자.
So picture what would happen if you took
a conv net and connected it to an RNN.
이미지가 들어오고, 어떤 sequence가 나옵니다.
You have an image going in, and
a sequence of things coming out.
아마도 단어의 sequence.
A sequence of words maybe.
그 이미지에 대한 caption이 가능합니다.
Maybe the caption for that image.
이것을 하기 위해서는,
이미지들와 captions을 훈련시키는 것이 필요합니다.
To do that,
you need training images and captions.
그것을 하기 위한 몇가지 데이터 셋을 만들수 있다.
There are a few data sets out
there that you can use for that.
대부분은 coco 데이터 셋입니다.
Most notably the coco data set.
그것은 이미지들과 이미지에 대한
crowdsourced captions이다.
It does images and
crowdsourced captions for them.
이미지들을 분석하고 captions을 생성하기 위해서
cov net을 사용해서 모델을 학습할 수 있습니다.
You can train a model that uses
a cov net to analyze the image and
generate captions from them.
이것은 작동한다.
And it works.
완벽하게 자동으로 생성하는 훌륭한
captions을 얻을 수 있습니다.
You can get great captions,
generated completely automatically, and
때로는 아주 재미있는 방법으로 실패합니다.
it sometimes fails in very,
very funny ways.